Finding Aid for Division of Research Development and Administration (University of Michigan) Records, 1919-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administrative Files 1922-1972
  - Committees
    - Research Policy (S. J. Axelrodi) 1958 (Box 15)
  - Consultants-Payment of 1956, 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Copyright for Research 1955 (Box 15)
  - Cost of Research
    - Correspondence and Graphs 1957-1960 (Box 15)
    - Statistics 1953-1961 (Box 15)
  - Directory 1957-1962 (Box 15)
  - Editorial Office 1962-1967 (Box 15)
  - Equipment-Care of 1957 (Box 15)
  - Faculty and Administrators
    - General 1949-1957, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Emeritus Professors 1955 (Box 15)
    - Government Contracts 1946-1952 (Box 15)
    - Biographical Sketches
      - Boyd, Robert A. (Project Representative) 1957-1963 (Box 15)
      - Frederick, Julian R. (Project Representative) 1954-1955 (Box 15)
      - White, Albert E. (Director 1920-1953) 1948-1958 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships
    - Engineering Research Institute (Sponsored Research) 1949-1962, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Other 1955-1957 (Box 15)
  - Finance
    - Account Definitions 1956-1970 (Box 15)
    - Allocated Direct Costs 1955-1961, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Compensatory Time 1957 (Box 15)
    - Financial Statements 1962-1971 (Box 15)
  - Grant Cost Sharing 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - Hardship Procedures 1965-1972 (Box 15)
  - Instrument Shop 1955
    - Report-"Recommendations On Transferring To Engineering Research Institute" 1955 (Box 15)
  - Insurance 1950-1962 (Box 15)
  - Laboratories
    - Cyclotron 1962-1963 (Box 15)
    - Daylighting 1946-1957 (Box 15)
    - Fluids 1953-1958 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous 1954-1958 (Box 15)
    - Radiation 1957-1961
      - Reports, 1953-1958 (Box 15)
      - Siegel, K. M. 1961 (Box 15)
    - Rocket 1950-1958 (Box 15)
      (formerly Rocket Propulsion)
    - Vision Research 1954-1958 (Box 15)
      (Blackwell, H. R. and Project MICHIGAN)
  - Management Information Systems 1969 (Box 16)
  - NASA-AMES University Consortium 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - National Research Council
    - Committee on Undersea Warfare 1955-1956 (Box 16)
    - International Geophysical Year 1955-1957 (Box 16)
  - National Science Foundation 1957-1959
    - Reductions 1968-1969 (Box 16)
  - North Campus (including shuttle car) 1953, 1957
    - Machine Shop-Creation of 1952-1964, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Overruns 1959-1965
    - Statistics 1962-1966 (Box 16)
  - Organization 1950-1970
    - Employee Position Descriptions 1954-1957 (Box 16)
  - Parking 1956-1957 (Box 16)
  - Personnel
    - Personnel Office (Acer, A. B.) 1948-1960 (Box 16)
    - Employee Titles 1952-1960, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Organization 1957 (Box 16)
    - Procedures 1953-1961, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Retirement Plan 1939-1961 (Box 16)
  - Photographic Department 1950-1963 (Box 16)
  - Preliminary Research 1961-1966 (Box 16)
  - Procedures 1962-1970
    - Reports and Forms 1968-1971 (Box 16)
    - Forms 1955-1958 (Box 16)
  - Property Control 1953-1959 (Box 16)
  - Publications Administration (D. Thackery) 1962-1970 (Box 16)
  - Quarterly Reports on Proposals 1962-1970 (Box 16)
  - Questionnaire-"Research Activities" (Selected Comments) 1967 (Box 16)
  - Research
    - Air Pollution Research Panel 1956-1958 (Box 16)
    - Acoustics b(including Acoustics Advisory Committee) 1954-1958 (Box 16)
    - Civil Defense 1954 (Box 16)
      (Courtis, J. W. and W. E. Mallory and Co.)
    - Phoenix Project 1952-1966
      - Materials Testing Reactor 1955-1956 (Box 16)
      - Nuclear Reactor 1954-1957 (Box 16)
    - Project MICHIGAN
      - North Campus Building 1956-1959 (Box 16)
      - Flood, M. M. 1956-1958 (Box 16)
    - Radiation 1951, 1954, 1957 (Box 16)
    - Radio Astronomy 1969-1973 (Box 16)
    - Soil Contingency 1956-1957 (Box 16)
    - Research Development Group 1969-1970 (Box 16)
    - Sea Grant Program 1971 (Box 16)
  - Service Facilities-Machine Shop and Technical Printing 1957-1958 (Box 16)
  - Space Allocation 1949-1969, 2 folders
    - Reports 1950-1956 (Box 16)
  - Sponsored Research 1962-1968 (Box 16)
  - Status Reports 1957 (Box 16)
  - Student Employment 1964, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Termination of Projects 1957-1958 (Box 17)
  - University of Michigan News Service 1962 (Box 17)
  - Visitors 1958-1962
    - Haley, Andrew G. and Dr. Heinrich Welf, Prince of Hannover 1956-1958 (Box 17)
- Correspondence Files 1943-1972
  The Correspondence Files cover the years from 1943 to 1972. Again, as with the Administrative Files, the majority of material covers the 1950s and early 1960s. The series is divided into two major subseries: "University of Michigan Correspondence" and "Non-University of Michigan Correspondence." The University of Michigan Correspondence contains letters and memos to and from university administrators, colleges, schools, centers, and institutes. Most of the correspondence is not outstanding, but does establish the relationship between the DRDA and the research community at the university. One file, that of Vice-President (for Research) Ralph A. Sawyer does contain more substantive information and helps document the relationship between the newly-founded Office of the Vice-President for Research and the renamed UMRI.
  - University of Michigan Correspondence
    - Administration
      - President, Office of (Williams, R. L.) 1952-1962, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Vice-President and Dean of Faculties (Niehuss, Marvin L.) 1954-1962 (Box 17)
      - Vice-President for Academic Affairs (Smith, A. F.) 1968-1972 (Box 17)
      - Vice-President for Research
        - Sawyer, Ralph A. (V-P 1959-1964)
          - Advisory Committee on Use of Water Pollution Laboratory, Meeting Minutes 1963 (Box 17)
          - Annual Reports
            - V-P for Research 1959/60-1962/63 (Box 17)
            - University of Michigan Research Institute 1959/60 (Box 17)
          - Committee on Pre-requisites and Titles for Research Appointees 1958-1963 (Box 17)
          - Dual Overhead 1962
            - Statistics 1948-1964 (Box 17)
          - Facilities
            - Research Space
              - Main and North Campus 1959-1963 (Box 17)
              - Willow Run Laboratories 1959-1960, 1962 (Box 17)
            - Radiation Laboratory (Seigel, K. M.) 1960 (Box 17)
            - St. Ignace Docks-Purchase of 1961 (Box 17)
          - Institute of Science and Technology
            - Annual Reports 1959/60, 1961/62, 1962/63 (Box 17)
            - Mars Trip Project 1962 (Box 17)
          - List of Research Institutes and Museums at UM 1960 (Box 17)
          - Meade, George (Congressman) 1960-1964 (Box 17)
          - Medical School Correspondence 1960-1964 (Box 17)
          - National Bureau of Standards 1961 (Box 17)
          - National Federation of College and University Business Officers Association-Committee on Governmental Relations 1962 (Box 17)
            (includes 1962 questionnaire)
          - National Science Foundation-Changes in Research Regulations 1960-1962 (Box 17)
          - Overruns on Sponsored Research Projects 1960-1964 (Box 17)
          - Overhead Computation 1960-1963 (Box 17)
          - Procedures for Processing Research Proposals 1960-1963 (Box 17)
          - Project MICHIGAN 1962 (Box 17)
          - Radiation Laboratory 1960-1964
            - UMRI Report 1959 (Box 17)
          - United States Government
            - Health, Education, and Welfare, Dept. of 1962-1963
              - Overhead Limitation Debate 1961-1963 (Box 17)
            - Army Audit Agency 1959-1964, 2 folders
              - Fort Monmouth Renegotiation 1960-1963 (Box 17)
        - Norman, Arthur G. (V-P 1964-1972)
          - Correspondence files 1964-1971, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - Business Office
        - Lee, G. L., correspondence 1951-1965, 4 folders (Box 17)
        - Hanes, C. E., correspondence 1967-1970 (Box 17)
        - Pierpont, W. K., correspondence 1952-1968 (Box 17)
        - Accounting Dept. 1968-1971 (Box 17)
      - Controller, Office of (Cottrell, H. R.) 1963-1969 (Box 17)
      - Purchasing Dept. 1961-1970 (Box 17)
    - Colleges, Schools, Centers, and Institutes
      - Aerospace Engineering, Dept. of 1952-1969
        - High Altitude Laboratory 1972 (Box 17)
      - Anthropology, Dept. of 1971 (Box 17)
      - Astronomy, Dept. of 1961-1964 (Box 17)
      - Bacteriology, Dept of 1961-1962 (Box 17)
      - Biological Chemistry, Dept. of 1959-1960, 1966, 1970 (Box 17)
      - Botany, Dept. of 1961, 1965-1970 (Box 17)
      - Chemistry, Dept. of 1952-1959 (Box 17)
      - Chemistry and Metallurgical Engineering, Dept. of 1952-1969 (Box 18)
      - Civil Engineering, Dept. of 1953-1970
        - Hewson, E. W. 1953-1954 (Box 18)
      - Dentistry, School of 1964-1971 (Box 18)
      - Dermatology, Dept. of 1959, 1969 (Box 18)
      - Education, School of 1969-1970 (Box 18)
      - Electrical Engineering, Dept. of 1951-1971, 4 folders
        - Radiation Laboratory 1955-1956 (Box 18)
      - Engineering, College of 1952-1967
        - Dean's Office (Brown, G. G.) 1951-1956 (Box 18)
        - Ohlgren, H. A. (Professor) 1953-1958 (Box 18)
      - Fluids Engineering (Report-"Faculty Requirements for F. E. Laboratory) undated (Box 18)
      - Geography, Dept. of 1962, 1965 (Box 18)
      - Geology, Dept. of 1961-1969 (Box 18)
      - Great Lakes Research Institute 1954-1960 (Box 18)
      - Human Performance Center 1969 (Box 18)
      - Icing Research Center 1952-1954 (Box 18)
      - Industrial Engineering, Dept. of 1959-1972 (Box 18)
      - Internal Medicine, Dept. of 1962 (Box 18)
      - Kresge Hearing Research Institute 1969 (Box 18)
      - Language and Language Behavior, Center for Research on 1968
      - Learning and Teaching, Center for Research on 1972 (Box 18)
      - Literature, Science, and Arts, College of 1951-1970, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Mathematics, Dept. of 1953-1969 (Box 18)
      - Mechanical Engineering, Dept. of 1952-1972, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Medical School 1960-1972 (Box 18)
      - Meteorology and Oceanography, Dept. of 1965-1972 (Box 18)
      - Michigan Historical Collections 1961, 1968 (Box 18)
      - Michigan Research Foundation 1956-1963 (Box 18)
      - Physics, Dept. of 1952-1971 (Box 18)
      - Psychology, Dept. of 1958-1971 (Box 18)
      - Public Health, School of 1967-1972 (Box 18)
      - Public Policy, Institute of 1972 (Box 18)
      - Rackham Graduate School 1958-1970 (Box 18)
      - Science and Technology, Institute of 1958 (Box 18)
      - Social Research, Institute for 1954-1967 (Box 18)
      - University of Michigan-Flint Campus (French, D. M., Dean) 1959-1963 (Box 18)
      - Vision Research Center 1954-1958 (Box 18)
      - Vocational Education and Practical Arts, Dept of 1961 (Box 18)
      - Zoology, Dept. of 1961-1970 (Box 18)
  - Non-University of Michigan Correspondence
    - Businesses, Societies, and Associations
      - A. C. Sparkplug Division 1953, 1957-1958 (Box 18)
      - Advanced Research Projects Agency 1960 (Box 18)
      - Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Co. 1957-1960 (Box 18)
      - Aluminum Association 1960 (Box 18)
      - American Gas and Electric Corporation 1957-1958 (Box 18)
      - American Meteorological Society 1957 (Box 18)
      - American Photo-Copy Equipment Co. 1961 (Box 18)
      - American Society of Mechanical Engineers 1960 (Box 18)
      - American Society for Testing Materials 1960 (Box 18)
      - American Society of Tool Engineers 1955 (Box 18)
      - AMP Inc. 1958 (Box 18)
      - "A"-Miscellaneous 1961-1962 (Box 18)
      - Bendix Aviation Corp. 1957-1959 (Box 18)
      - Bruce, E. L. Co. 1961 (Box 18)
      - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Education 1958-1961 (Box 18)
      - Central American Research Institute for Industry 1957 (Box 18)
      - Chrysler Corp. 1957-1961 (Box 18)
      - DuPont de Nemours, and Co. 1955-1960 (Box 18)
      - Engineering College Research Council 1960-1962 (Box 18)
      - "E"-Miscellaneous 1958 (Box 18)
      - Ford Motor Co. 1954-1958 (Box 18)
      - Gardner-Denver Co. 1959 (Box 18)
      - General Electric Co. 1955-1961 (Box 18)
      - General Motors Corp. 1955-1962 (Box 18)
      - Goodrich, B. F., Co. 1958 (Box 18)
      - Great Lakes Carbon Corp. 1957 (Box 18)
      - Howell, Ward Associates, Inc. 1958-1959 (Box 18)
      - Jaqua Co. 1960 (Box 18)
      - Kaiser Aluminum and Chemical Sales, Inc. 1957 (Box 18)
      - Kellogg Foundation 1959 (Box 18)
      - Ladish Co. 1957 (Box 19)
      - Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Co. 1957-1958 (Box 19)
      - Lockheed Aircraft Corp. 1957-1958 (Box 19)
      - "L"-Miscellaneous,1962 (Box 19)
      - Martin, Glenn L. Co. 1956 (Box 19)
      - McDonnell Aircraft Corp. 1956-1957 (Box 19)
      - McGraw Hill Co. (Exhibits) 1956 (Box 19)
      - McKee, Arthur G. and Co. 1958 (Box 19)
      - Metallurgical Engineers, Inc. 1957 (Box 19)
      - Modine Manufacturing Co. 1954-1956 (Box 19)
      - Mueller Brass Co. 1955-1958 (Box 19)
      - National Electrical Manufacturers Association 1956 (Box 19)
      - National Research Council 1954 (Box 19)
      - Portland Cement Association 1957 (Box 19)
      - Radio Bible Class 1958 (Box 19)
      - Sackner Products, Inc. 1956-1958 (Box 19)
      - Sears, Roebuck and Co. 1958 (Box 19)
      - Spencer Chemical Co. 1953-1955 (Box 19)
      - Sperry Products, Inc. 1943-1957 (Box 19)
      - Suffrin, Harry, Clothier (Detroit) 1957 (Box 19)
      - Taylor Instrument Co. 1955-1958 (Box 19)
      - Texas Co. (Texaco) 1955-1956 (Box 19)
      - United States Rubber Co. 1956-1958 (Box 19)
      - University Microfilms 1968 (Box 19)
      - Warner and Swassey Co. 1956-1957 (Box 19)
      - Westinghouse Electric Co. 1955-1961 (Box 19)
      - Whirlpool Co. 1960 (Box 19)
      - Wyandotte Chemicals Corp. 1959 (Box 19)
    - Universities (Other than UM)
      - Alabama, U. of 1960-1961 (Box 19)
      - Alberta (Canada), U. of 1962 (Box 19)
      - Buffalo, U. of 1958 (Box 19)
      - California, U. of 1962-1966 (Box 19)
      - City College (New York) 1960-1961 (Box 19)
      - Colorado, U. of 1962 (Box 19)
      - Dayton, U. of 1958, 1961 (Box 19)
      - Delaware, U. of 1959 (Box 19)
      - Illinois, U. of 1958-1960 (Box 19)
      - Indonesia, U. of (Universiteit Indonesia) 1958 (Box 19)
      - Kansas State College 1956 (Box 19)
      - Kentucky Research Foundation 1956, 1959, 1961 (Box 19)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology 1954-1958 (Box 19)
      - New York U. 1956 (Box 19)
      - North Carolina State College 1955 (Box 19)
      - Oberlin (Ohio) College 1961 (Box 19)
      - Ohio State U. 1955-1960 (Box 19)
      - Oregon, U. of 1966 (Box 19)
      - Princeton U. 1955-1961 (Box 19)
      - Purdue U. 1955-1960 (Box 19)
      - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute 1957
        - Folsom, R. G. (President) 1958-1962 (Box 19)
      - Tulane U. 1957-1960 (Box 19)
    - Individuals
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1957-1962 (Box 19)
      - Kriege, Herbert F., Consulting Chemist 1957 (Box 19)
    - Governments
      - Michigan, State of-Miscellaneous 1957-1967 (Box 19)
      - United States
        - Air Force 1961-1966
          - Electronic Systems Division 1957, 1961-1962 (Box 19)
          - Systems Command 1957-1967, 3 folders (Box 19)
        - Armed Services Technical Information Agency 1952-1955 (Box 19)
        - Army 1960-1967
          - Audit Agency 1962 (Box 19)
          - Chemical Corps 1953-1962 (Box 19)
          - Detroit Ordnance District 1958-1962 (Box 19)
          - Army Electronics Material Agency (Signal Corps) 1956-1962 (Box 19)
          - Medical Research-Development Command 1964-1965 (Box 19)
          - Office of Ordinance Research 1952-1953, 1956-1959 (Box 19)
          - Office of Scientific Research 1958-1963 (Box 19)
        - Atomic Energy Commission 1960-1964, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - Congress 1958, 1962 (Box 19)
        - Defense, Dept. of 1954-1962 (Box 19)
        - Health, Education, and Welfare, Dept. of 1960-1964
          - Public Health Service 1964 (Box 19)
        - Interior, Dept. of-Bureau of Mines 1966-1968 (Box 19)
        - Maritime Administration 1955-1956 (Box 19)
        - National Aeronautics and Space Administration 1958-1965 (Box 19)
        - National Archives 1960 (Box 19)
        - National Institutes of Health 1959-1962 (Box 19)
        - National Science Foundation 1954-1963, 3 folders (Box 19)
        - Navy 1955-1960
          - Office of Naval Research 1946-1967 (Box 19)
        - Ordinance Corp-Watertown Arsenal 1953, 1959, 1961 (Box 19)
        - Rome Air Development Center 1956-1963 (Box 19)
- Willow Run Laboratories 1946-1966
  The records of the Willow Run Laboratories (WRL) an alphabetical, subject-oriented sequence. There are a couple of folders containing short biographies of members of the staff from the late 1950s and another large series dealing with the buildings at the WRL. Also, a selection of "Research Proposals" help document the types of research the WRL sought.
  - General 1946-1966, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Annual Report, circa 1950, 1959/60 (Box 19)
  - Audit 1952-1953 (Box 19)
  - Biographies
    - "Selected", circa 1958 (Box 19)
    - "Senior Academic Appointees" 1959 (Box 19)
  - Buildings
    - Building Alterations-General 1954-1966 (Box 20)
    - Phase III-General 1955-1960
      - Blue Prints (Box 20)
      - Report ("Willow Run Lab. Phase III Remodeling") 1956 (Box 20)
    - Hangar #2-General 1955-1959
      - Rehabilitation Plan (Report) 1956 (Box 20)
    - Industry Sponsored Projects and Use of Equipment 1956 (Box 20)
    - Packard Hangar 1957-1961 (Box 20)
    - Space Allocation 1954-1958 (Box 20)
    - Space Planning 1954-1958 (Box 20)
  - Conference Meetings-Report (Optical Society) 1959 (Box 20)
  - Executive Committee
    - General 1958-1960 (Box 20)
    - Meeting Minutes 1958-1960, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Financial Summaries December 1956, January 1957 (Box 20)
  - New Projects Committee 1957 (Box 20)
  - Operations Research Committee 1956-1958 (Box 20)
  - Organization 1958 (Box 20)
  - Patent Procedures 1952 (Box 20)
  - Personnel 1957-1959 (Box 20)
  - Procedures 1951, 1955-1957 (Box 20)
  - Publications 1957-1960 (Box 20)
  - Research Planning Staff 1957 (Box 20)
  - Research Proposals
    - Rejected 1958-1959 (Box 20)
    - Reports 1958 (Box 20)
    - Summaries 1958-1960, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Status Reports 1957-1958 (Box 20)
  - Rocket Test Site 1958-1960 (Box 20)
  - Technical Documents Services 1957-1958
    - Farrell, T. 1956-1958 (Box 20)
    - Publications 1957 (Box 20)
  - Technical Operations Staff 1957 (Box 20)
  - Wind Tunnel (Supersonic) 1951-1959 (Box 20)
- Directors’ Files
  The Directors' Files contain the records of James Lesch, director of the DRDA from the early 1970s to the mid 1980s and Allen Steiss, director from 1988 to 1996. The James Lesch subseries is divided into three broad categories: "Subject Files," "DRDA Correspondence Files," and "Chronological Files." The subject files contain information about the administrative aspects of both modern-day research and the running of a research unit in a large university. They are closely tied with the records of the Office of the Vice-President for Research. The second and third series are the un-edited run of correspondence and other materials that would comprise a chronological file from 1971 to 1988. The Allen Steiss subseries is similarly divided into "Correspondence Files," containing monthly in/out files for the entire period of his directorship, and "Topical Files."
  - James Lesch (1969-1988)
    - Subject Files
      - Academic Affairs Information 1983-1987 (Box 21)
      - Ad Hoc Committee to Review the Classified Research Policy 1985-1987
        - Reports 1986 (Box 21)
      - Alumni Research Advisory Committee 1983-1985 (Box 21)
      - Ann Arbor-Business Environment Report 1985 (Box 21)
      - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce 1984-1987 (Box 21)
      - Ann Arbor Nuclear, Inc. (H. J. Gomberg) 1981-1986 (Box 21)
      - Association of American Universities (University-Industry Relationships and Technology Transfer) 1985-1987 (Box 21)
      - Awards
        - PRISM Awards 1979-1984 (Box 21)
        - Awards Received by Sponsors-Quarterly Reports, FY 1980-FY 1984 (Box 21)
      - Budget
        - General 1987 (Box 21)
        - Fiscal Year 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 21)
        - Budget Materials 1986 (Box 21)
        - FY 1988 Request, 1987 (Box 21)
      - Center For Information Technology Integration 1985-1987 (Box 21)
      - Charitable Donations-Procedures 1983 (Box 21)
      - Conflict of Interest and Commitment Task Force 1982-1986
        - Report 1985 (Box 21)
      - Council on Government Relations-Meeting Reports and UM Comments on Issues 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Cost Sharing 1985-1987 (Box 21)
      - Equipment Planning 1983-1984 (Box 21)
      - Directors
        - Lesch, James E., Biographical Information (Box 21)
        - Tobin, Martin-Acting Director 1987 (Box 21)
      - DRDA/Office of Vice President for Research (OVPR) Administrative Relationships 1972-1974 (Box 21)
      - Ethics in Research (Academic Integrity) 1983-1987 (Box 21)
      - Foreign Research Funding-U.S. General Accounting Office Questionnaire 1987 (Box 21)
      - Functions and Operations-General 1986 (Box 21)
      - Governor's Task Force on Higher Education 1984 (Box 21)
      - Industrial Affiliation Agreements 1969, 1979-1987, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Information Management and Communication, Committee on (CIMAC)
        - Background Materials 1982-1986 (Box 21)
        - Correspondence (includes PRISM reports) 1982-1987 (Box 21)
        - "Status Report on Information Technology Developments," 1986 (Box 21)
      - Indirect Costs
        - General 1983, 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Ad Hoc Committee on 1981-1983 (Box 22)
          - Reports 1983 (Box 22)
        - Projection Statistics 1986-1987 (Box 22)
        - Rate Agreements 1980-1986 (Box 22)
      - Information Systems Design and Optimization Systems/Meta Systems 1984-1987 (Box 22)
      - Institute for Social Research (Box 22)
      - Insurance Related to Research Projects 1983 (Box 22)
      - Intellectual Properties Office 1984-1987, 6 folders (Box 22)
      - Machine Vision 1986 (Box 22)
      - Manufacturing Sciences, National Center for 1986 (Box 22)
      - Medical School 1971-1985 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Biotechnology Institute 1982-1986 (Box 22)
      - Michigan High Technology Task Force 1983-1985 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Research Corp. 1982-1986, 3 folders
        - Incubator Facility-Human/Animal Treatment 1985-1987 (Box 22)
        - Reports and Background Materials 1981-1986 (Box 22)
      - Michigan, State of-Audit Report for UM 1979-1984 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Technological Council
        - General 1983-1986, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - Annual Report 1984 (Box 22)
        - Budget 1985 (Box 22)
        - Directors 1982-1986 (Box 22)
        - Reports 1985-1986 (Box 22)
        - South Central Division 1984-1986
          - Meeting Minutes 1984-1986, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - Statewide Meeting Minutes 1984-1986, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Non-Classified and Classified Research 1976, 1981-1986 (Box 23)
      - Non-Classified Research Review 1983-1984 (Box 23)
        (including comments on the Research Policies Committee)
      - Nuclear Activation Services, LTD 1984-1985 (Box 23)
      - Office of Vice President for Research
        - Merger with Graduate School-Report of the Planning Committee 1984 (Box 23)
        - Report of the Committee to Study OVPR 1971 (Box 23)
        - OVPR Correspondence File
          - General 1983, 1986-1987 (Box 23)
          - Cost Sharing Report 1986 (Box 23)
          - Gifts and Grants 1985-1986 (Box 23)
          - Industrial Liaisons 1986 (Box 23)
          - National Council of University Research Administration Survey 1986 (Box 23)
          - OVPR Funds 1986-1987 (Box 23)